美国巴林海军支援设施
晚上好 Hill先生
Good evening, Mr. Hill.
你好吗
How you doing?
== 海军罪案调查处:洛杉矶 第五季 第10集 ==
【H-SGDK】字幕组倾情奉献
== 翻译：一直向左走 特特 暮暮 尧之雪 小怪 ==
== 校对&时间轴：小怪 天之行者  ==
== 后期&统筹：尧之雪 封装：天之行者 ==
本字幕仅用于交流 学习之用
禁止用于任何商业用途 否则后果自负
发生了什么
What the...?
这屋子里透着诡异
Anomaly in the room.
Deeks竟然在辛勤工作
Deeks hard at work.
Deeks居然没话痨
Deeks not talking.
真有趣
Interesting.
嗯哼 太有趣了
Mm-hmm. Very interesting.
有趣吗 一点也没有
Interesting? No, no.
我 呃 才不有趣
I'm, uh, not interesting.
现在越来越逗了
Now that's interesting.
Deeks 别介意哈
Don't mind us, Deeks.
都不瞧我们一眼
Won't make eye contact.
心率升高
Elevated heart rate.
坐立不安 还不是咖啡的缘故
Fidgety... not from the coffee.
出汗 也不是因为气候
Sweaty... and it's not the climate.
拜托了
Come on, guys.
开始辩解了
Defensive.
我只是 我觉得也许是
I just... I think that maybe
因为今天喝的咖啡比较浓而已
the coffee is just stronger today.
开始转移话题了
Changing the subject.
他今天有熊猫眼
And he's got some dark rings under his eyes.
早上好
Morning.
你的搭档今天很怪异
Your partner's acting weird.
- 我搭档就是怪胎  - 她说的对
- My partner is weird. - She has a point.
喔 毫无反应
Oh, he's unresponsive.
独具创造性的回避方法
Creative avoidance.
你怎么看
What do you think?
你怎么穿的跟昨天一样
Isn't that the same shirt you had on yesterday?
哇
Wow.
这可是第一次
This is a first.
你们俩就没什么要说的吗
Neither of you have anything to say.
不不 我
No, no, I...
有案子 简短报告
Case on deck, quick briefing,
我们今天有战术任务了
and then our day gets tactical.
- 你先走  - 不 你先走 不 你先走
- Go ahead. - No, go ahead. No, go ahead.
- 不好意思  - 不 你该先走
- Sorry. - No, I think you should go first,
- 我们得去行动中心...  - 好吧
- 'cause we should go to ops... - Okay.
分开走
separately.
不会 才不是我想的
No... no...
才不是
No!
你在想什么
A penny for your thoughts?
早就涨价了
Price has gone up.
分享个故事都不能给个折扣
There's no discount for shared history?
不行 对你没有折扣
No, no discount for you,
因为你恰巧是少数几个懂得交易成本的人
because you're one of the few who understand the cost.
听着像是在恭维我
That sounds like a compliment.
或者是诅咒
Or a curse.
还有些其他事儿浮出水面了
Something else has come up.
不是什么好事儿
You're not gonna like it.
两国交兵不斩来使
Don't shoot the messenger.
这只是时间问题
It was only a matter of time.
24小时前 一位名叫Ron Hill的
24 hours ago, a Pentagon consultant
五角大楼顾问在巴林海军中心指挥部被杀
named Ron Hill was murdered at the Naval Central Command in Bahrain.
他为联合特种作战司令部制定应急方案
He created contingencies for Joint Special Operations Command.
防备全球不可预知事件的发生
The art of gaming unpredictable global events.
他正打算传送一份夺取巴基斯坦核军火库的方案
And he was about to deliver a plan for seizing Pakistan's nuclear arsenal
如果发生政变 美国政府想确保那些
If a coup happens, the United States wants to make sure
大规模杀伤性武器不会落入敌手
those WMDs don't fall in the wrong hands.
问题是 应急计划双方都能利用
Problem is, contingency plans cut both ways.
对我们来说 是解决之道
For us, it's a solution.
而对对方来说 则是个机会
For the other side, it's an opportunity.
保护巴基斯坦核武的计划 也可以借览成
The plan to secure Pakistan's nukes could also be exploited
盗取的计划
as a plan to steal them.
Hill把文件传到了U盘上
Hill transferred the plan to a thumb drive.
仅此一份 不可复制
It was the only copy, impossible to duplicate.
黑市上许多买家对这种情报垂涎三尺
Lot of buyers in the black market for intel like that.
别忘了 还有很多杀手
Lot of murder suspects, too.
凶手轻车熟路
Killer knew his blade.
一刀砍头 这本事可不小
Taking a head with one cut takes skill.
我以前去过巴林基地
I've been to that base in Bahrain.
廓尔喀人负责看守
Gurkhas pull security there.
廓什么 是谁
Gerka-what? Who?
是十四岁就从尼泊尔深山里征募的部队
Commandos recruited from the mountains of Nepal at age 14.
给他们把枪 他们能毁掉一个射击场
Hand 'em a gun, and they'll tear up a shooting range.
给他们把刀 他们能悄无声息地毁灭整个城市
You hand them a knife, they'll wipe out an entire city without making a noise.
他们擅长各种兵刃 但是以廓尔喀刀闻名
They're good with any blade, but they made the kukri famous.
他们就是传奇
They're legendary.
廓尔喀人平均身高一米六 125磅重
The average Gurkha's about 5'4'', 125 pounds,
有传闻说 他们在阿富汗杀死的人比其他军队都多
and rumor has it, they stacked more kills in Afghanistan than anyone else,
除了美国和英国以外
except for America and England.
没有什么比一个拿着刀的男人更能激发你内心的狂热了
Well, nothing brings out your inner fangirl like a guy with a knife.
Hill被杀当晚负责安保的 事实上 确实是廓尔喀人
Security detail in Bahrain on the night of Hill's murder were, in fact, Gurkhas
从印度军队借调过来的
on loan from India's Army.
他们宣称关于Hill的谋杀案 是被陷害的
And they claim they're being framed for Hill's murder.
Eric 你说过我们要进行战术行动
Eric, you said we were going tactical?
U盘内存储的归航信标
Homing beacon planted inside the thumb drive
显示其现在正位于好莱坞的一间旅馆内
shows that it's now located in this Hollywood hotel.
如果我们要跟廓尔喀人交手呢
And what if we're fighting Gurkhas?
保护好你的脖子
Protect your neck.
我们在二楼
We're on the second floor.
房间号255
Room 255.
GPS信号只能精确到十英尺的范围
A GPS beacon's accurate to ten feet.
U盘不是在那个房间
The thumb drive's either in that room,
就是在正下方的那间
or the one directly below it.
正在接近155号房间
Approaching room 155.
准备破门
Ready to breach.
听我口令
On my count.
三 二
Three... two...
一
...one.
联邦探员
Federal agents!
安全
Clear.
Kens
Kens!
你还好吗
You good?
北侧停车场有枪手正在移动
We've got an active shooter in the north lot.
我们正在追
We're moving.
- 我们分开追 拦住他  - 好
- Split up, cut him off.   - Check.
Deeks Kensi 走廊里击毙一人
Deeks, Kensi, one hostile down in the hallway.
没有U盘
No thumb drive.
嗨 你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
是吗 你叫什么名字
Yeah? What's your name?
- 我叫 Maddie  - 是Maddie吗
- Maddie. - Maddie?
- 好的 听着...  - 放下武器
- All right, look... - Drop your weapons.
没事儿的
It's okay.
你会没事儿的 Maddie
You're gonna be fine, Maddie.
好吗
Okay?
这刀不错
Nice knife.
让这个小女孩离开
Please let the girl go.
你走吧
Get out of here.
快跑
Run.
Run!
- Kensi你在哪儿  - Deeks 这儿
- Kensi?! - Deeks!
走开 否则我让她血溅当场
Move, and I'll empty her guts all over the pavement.
开枪
Take the shot.
放下武器
Drop it!
快开枪
Take the shot.
快 我们走
Come on, let's go!
开枪啊
Send it.
上车
Get in!
你怎么样
You okay?
我没机会开枪
I didn't have a shot.
嗨
Hey.
听我说 我没机会开枪
Listen, I didn't have a shot.
我压根没机会
I didn't have a shot!
U盘
Thumb drive?
GPS信号消失了
GPS beacon's down.
他们一定破解了我们的追踪方法
They must have figured out how we tracked them.
这帮人不是廓尔喀人
They weren't Gurkhas.
体型太大 话太多
Too big. Too loud.
没有作战技巧
No finesse.
他们是巴基斯坦人
They were Pakistani.
你放倒的枪手
The shooter you took down
是一名三军情报局的特工
was an Inter-Services Intelligence agent
非官方身份的卧底
working under non-official cover.
廓尔喀人服役于印度军队
Gurkhas serve in the Indian military.
巴基斯坦和印度是毗邻的竞争对手
Pakistan and India are rivals who share a border.
有很多历史纷争
There's a lot of history there.
许多仇恨
Lot of hate.
Hill起草计划来夺取巴基斯坦核武
Hill drew up the plan to seize the Pakistan nukes.
他们得确定这份计划不会流传出去
They'd love to make sure it never got out.
偷一个U盘并且陷害他们最大的敌人
Well, stealing a thumb drive and framing your worst enemy for murder
- 兵行险招  - 有什么想法呢
- it's a pretty bold move. - Thoughts?
这符合巴基斯坦情报机关的思维
It's consistent with our profile of the Pakistani spy agency's mindset.
附议
Agreed.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
- 有什么事吗  - 是的
- Something we should know? - Yeah.
还有两名ISI特工还未到案
Two more ISI agents are on the loose,
他们手上有U盘
and they have the thumb drive.
找到他们
Find 'em.
好的
Okay.
24小时之前 你本该抓住机会开枪
24 hours ago, you would have taken that shot.
- 我没有机会  - 不 你有的
- I didn't have the shot. - Yes, you did.
好吧 昨天 我是该开枪的
Okay, yesterday, I would have taken the shot,
但现在已经不是昨天了 对吗
but it's not yesterday anymore... is it?
对吗
Is it?
发生了什么
What happened out there?
跟往常行动没什么区别
Same thing that happens every time we go kinetic.
有些意外的事情发生了 我们赶紧补救
Variables got in the way, and decisions were made.
我们正在进行行动后的汇报
We ran our after-action debrief,
正有所进展
and we're moving forward.
但是意外还没解决啊 Hanna先生
But the variables are still out there, Mr. Hanna.
我们会找回U盘的
We'll recover the thumb drive.
我不是在说U盘
The thumb drive is not what I'm referring to.
你的队伍 准备好出任务了吗
Is your team mission-ready?
希望吧
I hope so.
这个嘛 希望可不是个计划 Callen先生
Well, hope is not a plan, Mr. Callen.
好吧
Okay.
我该开枪的
I should have taken the shot,
我让我的感情妨碍了工作 很抱歉
and I let my emotions get in the way, and I'm sorry.
我真的尽力做到感情和工作互不干涉了
I'm honestly just trying to make this work.
这不可能的
It's not going to work.
我好像正站在冰冻的湖面上
I'm standing on my frozen lake.
我不知道你什么意思
I don't know what that means.
这是我从菲律宾格斗课学到的
It's something that I learned in Sayoc.
冰湖这个词 代表你在这世上
Your frozen lake is the name for what you want
最想要的东西 你想拥有它
the most in the world, and you want it...
你渴求得到它
you want it so bad
宁愿为此付出一切
that you'll do anything to get it.
你的心在驱使着行动
And your heart takes over.
但是正因如此
But because of that...
它最后会毁了你
it destroys you in the end.
你想要的就在那儿 就在冰封的湖面中间待着
It's right there, just sitting in the middle of this frozen lake.
你觉得自己速度够快
And you think you're fast enough to...
能在冰面碎裂之前 过去抓住它
to go out there and grab it before the ice cracks...
不过你没有发现的是
And what you don't realize is...
自己已经站在冰上
you're already standing on the ice
而且冰面正在你周围开裂
and it's falling apart around you.
呃 洛杉矶警方刚找到了尸体
Um, LAPD just found a body.
是旅店的其中一个枪手
One of the shooters from the hotel.
好勒
Good.
倒数第二个ISI特工
Second-to-last ISI agent.
一招毙命
One cut, one kill.
洛杉矶警方怎么说
What did LAPD say?
他们没找到U盘
They didn't find the thumb drive.
凶手消失得无影无踪
The last shooter's in the wind.
他们跑了
Well, they were on the run.
他们可能对事态升级情况达不成一致吧
Could've had a disagreement that escalated.
但是他们有枪
But they had guns.
如果情况恶化 为什么还非得用刀呢
If it escalated, why mess around with knives?
为什么不直接打死呢
Why not just shoot someone?
也许不是意见不合
Maybe it wasn't a disagreement.
可能是个埋伏
Maybe it was an ambush.
让一个极度反感被诬陷为谋杀
An ambush by someone who doesn't take kindly
和从事间谍活动的人伏击了
to being framed for murder and espionage.
有道理
Yeah.
他可能也没跑那么远
Maybe he's closer than we think.
Sam
Sam?
没错
Yup.
注意那把刀
Watch for the blade.
带刀来参加枪战 够他喝一壶了
Bring a knife to a gunfight, he'll see what happens.
没法开枪
No shot!
知道吗 这就是我说带刀来枪战的后果
What was that I said about bringing a knife to a gunfight?
没有U盘
No thumb drive.
你是谁
Who are you?
Jemadar Thapa
Jemadar Thapa,
廓尔喀第五步枪团
5th Gurkha Rifle Regiment,
边防部队
Frontier Force.
Jai Maa kali, Ayo Gorkhali
Jai Maa kali, Ayo Gorkhali.
"胜利归于吾神时母
"Victory to the Goddess Kali,
廓尔喀部队来了"
the Gurkhas are coming."
他们的作战口号
It's their war cry.
如果有人告诉你他不怕死
If a man tells you he's not afraid of dying
这人不是说谎就是廓尔喀人
he's either lying or he's a Gurkha.
你肯定听说过这个 对吧
I take it you've heard that one, huh?
从第一次说的人口中听来的
From the man who said it first,
已故陆军元帅Sam Manekshaw
the late Field Marshal Sam Manekshaw,
印度陆军参谋长
Indian Army Chief of Staff,
我的导师
my mentor.
嗯
Mm.
那他会支持你实施谋杀吗
Would he approve of you committing murder?
更别提在美国领土上袭击两名联邦探员了
Not to mention attacking two federal agents on American soil?
印度国防部
India's Ministry of Defense
派我来为廓尔喀正名
sent me here to clear the Gurkha name.
你为什么逃跑
Then why'd you run?
我不想在一个巴基斯坦间谍拿着
I did not want to waste time playing diplomat
敏感情报逃跑这种事情上花时间费口舌
while a Pakistani spy is on the run with sensitive intel.
如果我们想让你花时间 你现在就已经蹲监狱了
If we wanted to waste your time, you'd be in a prison right now.
顺便一提
And for the record,
那个敏感情报
that sensitive intel
由美国所有
is U.S. Property.
我不关心情报
The intel is not my concern.
没错 你在意的是复仇
No, your concern is revenge.
我管它叫荣誉
I call it honor.
荣誉吗
Honor?
你只为了这个才来这里吗 Thapa
Is that really the only reason you're here, Thapa?
我执行命令
I carry out my orders.
仅此而已
No more, no less.
没错 不过那个U盘还蛮有诱惑的 不是吗
Yeah, but that thumb drive's pretty tempting, isn't it?
挫败巴基斯坦核计划的行动方案
An operational plan to seize Pakistan's nukes;
让你们国家迫在眉睫的威胁彻底消失
to make the looming threat against your country disappear forever.
没准你的长官没告诉你要把它带回去
Maybe your command didn't tell you to bring it back...
但你要是带回去了 必定受到英雄般的欢迎
but you'd get a hero's welcome if you did.
就说你手上有U盘吧
Let's say you got your hands on the thumb drive.
你会说你会把它交给我们
You tell me you're just going to hand it over to us
然后一走了之吗
and walk away?
想让他交出U盘 必须经历一场恶战
There's no way he's giving up this thumb drive without a fight.
五角大楼说Thapa没问题
Pentagon says that Thapa checks out,
就是说官方已经确认他和我们在同一战线了
which means he's officially on our side.
他的妻子和三个孩子在西孟加拉邦
He's got a wife and three kids in West Bengal.
巴基斯坦只要一个袭击就能炸平那里
A strike by Pakistan would wipe them out.
你真觉得他能为了保证他们的安全而不去冒险吗
You really think he's going to give up a shot at keeping them safe?
只要他能控制情绪
If he can control his emotions.
事到行时才觉难啊
A lot easier said than done.
是啊 只要在意 就都不再简单了
Well, it's never easy when you start to care.
我猜那U盘就是他的冰湖吧
I guess this makes the thumb drive his frozen lake?
估计是了
Guess it does.
他会做正确的选择的
He'll do the right thing.
"白色幽灵"是个危险又诡秘的人
The White Ghost is a dangerous and elusive man.
这不是个简单的任务啊 Owen
This is not an easy mission, Owen.
所以我才亲自上阵
Which is why I'm running it myself.
你需要一个快速响应小组
You're going to need a QRF.
我让我的队伍随时待命
I'll keep my team on standby.
你在这儿掌能管一切 Henrietta
You've got your hands full right here, Henrietta,
不过我确实很感激这个提议
but I do appreciate the offer.
看来岁月让你变得温和了
It seems the years have made you kind.
有吗
Have they?
正在找最后的枪手 不过
Looking for the last shooter, but...
他参加过反监控训练 找他得花上大把时间
given his countersurveillance training, it's a long shot.
等一下 酒店那里用来逃跑的那辆车呢
Wait, what about the getaway car from the hotel?
它一直没出现
It still hasn't shown up.
我已经通过万花筒在找相同外观和型号的轿车了
I've got Kaleidoscope searching sedans of that make and model.
现在咱只能等了
Well, all we can do is wait.
我觉得
I think...
我不想知道你怎么想Kensi和Deeks的
I don't want to know what you think about Kensi and Deeks.
我没说我在想啊
I didn't say what I was thinking.
但是我知道你在想
But I know what you're thinking.
所以 你也在想这个
So, you're thinking it, too?
你觉得Hetty知道吗
You think Hetty knows?
我想 Hetty什么都知道
Hetty knows everything, I think.
咱俩想的一样
That's what I thought.
私人跑道
Private airstrip.
什么
Huh?
那个枪手 他得从美国逃走
The last shooter... he needs to leave the country
但是他的受训经验告诉他 要避开像洛杉矶国际机场这种枢纽
but he's trained to avoid major hubs like LAX
因为他知道我们会在哪里监控
because he knows that's where we'd be looking.
没错 但是万花筒已经找过私人停机坪了
Okay, but Kaleidoscope already searched private airstrip parking lots.
搜索私人停机坪周围的停机坪
Search major parking lots around the parking lots.
方圆五英里范围
In a five-mile radius.
离Pacoima的Whiteman机场
Sedan matching that description
两英里远有辆符合特征的车
two miles from Whiteman Airport in Pacoima.
没错 很合理 地方小 不是中央枢纽
Yep, makes sense... it's small, not a major hub.
我跟其他人说
I'll tell the others.
帮我接Callen探员
Get me Agent Callen.
明白 Hetty
Understood, Hetty.
咱得改变计划了
We got a change of plans.
Thapa跟着我们去跑道那里
Thapa's coming with us to the airstrip.
坏主意
It's a bad idea.
是啊 没准
Yeah, probably.
海军部长希望我们对他像自己的队友一样
SECNAV wants us to treat him like a member of the team.
她希望能促进我们和印度的关系
She's hoping to bolster relations with India.
海军部长从来没被这家伙的刀抵住过喉咙
SECNAV never had this little dude's knife to her throat.
我去枪械室给Thapa拿把枪
I'll get Thapa a gun from the armory.
不用 Deeks 把刀给他
No. Deeks, handle his stuff.
Kensi 你跟我和Sam走
Kensi, you're coming with Sam and me.
什
Wh...?
给你俩分开一下
You two could use some space.
明白
Understood.
有问题吗
You got this?
没问题
I got this.
欢迎入队
Welcome aboard.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗯 你的热枕势不可挡啊
Well, your enthusiasm is overwhelming.
我喜欢单独行动
I prefer to work alone.
我以前也这么觉得
Hmm, I used to feel the same way.
什么令你变了
What changed?
我发现有人值得去信任
I found somebody worth trusting.
你的队友信任我
And your team trusts me?
我不能替他们说 不过 呃
I can't really speak for my team, but, uh...
我相信你
...I do.
为什么
Why?
问得太好了
It's a damn good question.
我知道你想要U盘
I understand that you want the thumb drive.
而且我知道 如果我是你 我也想拿到
And I get that, 'cause if I was you, I'd want it, too.
因为这次行动 它让你变成了累赘
And for this mission, that makes you a liability.
但是你有能力
But you got this.
你相信我能办成
You believe I can do it?
我的理智可以胜过情感吗
That my brain will win over my heart?
兄弟 我得去相信
Brother, I got to believe that,
因为如果你能做到 我也能
'cause if you can do it, so can I.
Jemadar Thapa
Jemadar Thapa.
廓尔喀第五步枪团
5th Gurkha Rifle Regiment,
边防部队
Frontier Force.
Marty Deeks警探 洛杉矶警方
Detective Marty Deeks. LAPD.
廓尔喀的部队有句座右铭
The Gurkhas have a saying:
"宁可战死 不愿苟活"
"Better to die than be a coward."
哇哦 我觉得我搭档上辈子是个廓尔喀人
Wow. I think my regular partner was a Gurkha in a past life.
那他一定很勇敢
Then he must be brave.
应该是 她
Well, she...
她是最勇敢的
...she's the bravest.
我不会让您失望 先生
I will not let you down, sahib.
好的
Okay.
训练有素的巴基斯坦飞行员
Pakistani's a trained pilot.
只要一架飞机就能办成一切
All he's goona need is a plane.
风向合适吗
You got a good wind?
合适
Yeah.
角度没问题吧
Got yourself a nice angle?
没问题
Yep.
1500码也没问题
Still automatic from 1,500 yards?
对
Yep.
这孩子真爱敞开了说啊 是吧
Loves to open up about her feelings, doesn't she?
你从来没有搭档吗
So you've never had a partner?
没有
No.
廓尔喀部队没有女兵吗
There's no female Gurkhas?
没有
No.
那你就偷着乐去吧
Well, you should consider yourself lucky then.
我是说 你看我 我已经站在冰封的湖面了
I mean, look at me, I'm standing on a frozen lake.
我说话的感觉都有点像她了
And I'm beginning to sound like her.
人心需要自律
The heart needs discipline.
没有纪律 就没有荣誉
Without discipline there is no honor.
没有了荣誉 我们什么都不是
Without honor, we are nothing.
你知道吗 你还挺有意思的 Thapa
You know what, you're pretty cool, Thapa.
有那么一瞬间
For a second there, I forgot
我都忘了你今天早上还砍下了某人的头
that you chopped off some guy's head this morning.
要穿过冰封的湖面只有一个办法
There is only one way to cross a frozen lake.
ISI的特工已经抵达了跑道
The ISI agent has reached the airstrip.
他独自一人 走着来的
He's alone and on foot.
Deeks 待命
Stand by, Deeks.
看起来他要和别人会面
Looks like he's meeting somebody.
他不可能回到巴基斯坦
He will never make it back to Pakistan.
他的护照被标记了
His passport has been tagged.
他会被抓住的
He will be caught.
在Glendale的亚美尼亚犯罪集团
是洛杉矶附近办假证中最拿手的
Armenian Mob in Glendale has the best forgery operation in L.A.
他的第一件事肯定就是办个假护照
Fake passport would've been his first stop for sure.
这并不是问题
It does not matter.
- 他是个将死之人了  - 不 不 不
- He is a dead man. - No. No, no.
不要死人 好吗 我们得活捉他
No dead man, all right, we need to take him alive,
要不留痕迹 漂亮地完成 明白了吗
tie up any loose ends, you got that?
明白了 先生
Got it, sahib.
你一看见那个U盘 就行动
The moment you see that thumb drive, move in.
特工刚刚递了一个信封
Agent just passed an envelope.
可能是钱
I think it was money.
某种钥匙
Some sort of keys.
没看见U盘
No thumb drive visible.
不要
No.
Thapa
Thapa.
Deeks 行动
Deeks, move.
联邦探员
Federal agents!
放下武器
Drop it!
- 注意了望  - 收到
- Hold overwatch. - Check.
Thapa失踪了
Thapa's MIA.
Eric
Eric?
正在扫瞄跑道附近的摄像头
Scanning airstrip cams now.
Kensi
Kensi?
- 那个廓尔喀人去哪了  - 我看不见Thapa
- The Gurkha? - No visual on Thapa.
见鬼
Damn it.
不 不
No, no.
U盘不见了
Thumb drive's gone.
让我猜猜 你有个坏消息
Let me guess. You got bad news
然后还有个更坏的消息
and then you got "Fredo at the end of Godfather Part II" bad news.
棒级了 先告诉我坏消息吧
Awesome. Give me the bad news first.
这消息是不太好 但我不是送消息的人 Deeks
The news isn't good, but I'm not a messenger, Deeks.
那你是来给我加油打气的
So, what, you're the guy that gives me the pep talk?
我是来提醒你 你并不是孤军奋战
I'm the one that reminds you you're not in this alone.
坏消息是
Here's the bad news:
情况是 那巴基斯坦人
What happened was that the Pakistanis
今天早上 在网上找了个有飞机的人
found a plane owner online earlier today,
付钱让机主开飞机带他兜风
offered him cash for a ride. Owner had no idea
机主完全不知道他牵涉了什么
what he'd gotten himself into.
他在踏上跑道那刻就死了
Dead the moment he stepped on the tarmac.
好吧 告诉我那条更糟糕的消息
Okay. Give me Fredo.
Thapa溜了 而且没留下什么线索
Thapa's in the wind. No trace of him.
嗯 Eric正在从监控录像里搜索
Right. Eric's searching cam footage,
全州通缉 FBI 警犬队已经开始行动
statewide APB, FBI K-9 units are in route.
你觉得这些措施能阻止一个拿到了
And you think all that's enough to hunt down a Gurkha carrying the holy grail
绝密情报的廓尔喀军人吗
of intel in his pocket?
他的信用卡和银行账户都被冻结了
His credit cards and bank accounts are frozen.
印度政府因他违抗命令而将他除名了
Indian government disavowed him for violating direct orders.
这是个国际事件
This is an international incident.
Thapa是整个洛杉矶里的头号通缉犯
Thapa's the most wanted man in L.A.
我知道 而且是我相信了他
Yeah, I know. And I'm the one that trusted him.
- 可能你刚才没听见我说的话  - 我听见了
- Maybe you didn't hear me just now. - No, I did.
我不是孤军奋战 我明白
I'm not alone. I got it.
听着 呃
Listen, uh,
准确起见 是Kensi让我
just for the record, Kensi told me
在酒店里开火的
to take that shot at the hotel.
过去的我会开火
I've made that shot before. I've been there,
但我在那里 却没有开枪
I've done that, I got the T-shirt, I just didn't take it.
那让我们接着来
So get us back in the game.
我知道怎么找到Thapa并且拿回那个U盘
I know a way to find Thapa and get the thumb drive back.
看来你好像知道些我们所不知道的事
Something tells me you know something we don't.
很疯狂 不是吗
Crazy, right?
Hetty 我能处理好的
Hetty, I can make this right.
你有不少问题 Deeks先生
You have several problems, Mr. Deeks.
你想谈的是哪一个
Which one are we talking about?
我说的是那个廓尔喀人
I'm talking about the Gurkha.
我有个关于廓尔喀人的计划
I have a plan for the Gurkha.
啊
Ah.
我确信这会是个好主意
I'm sure it's brilliant.
告诉我
Tell me.
我真心觉得这人不会像个混混一样
I honestly don't think that this guy's gonna go rogue
把这个U盘拍卖出去
and sell the thumb drive to the highest bidder.
我是说 你想啊 他 他是个爱国者
I mean, think about this. He's a... he's a patriot,
他是个军人 如果他要把情报带回去
he's a soldier, and if he brings home the information
以打击巴基斯坦
to neutralize Pakistan, there's a good chance
印度很可能会让他回去的
India's gonna take him back.
嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
请求原谅总是比征得同意要好些
Always better to beg forgiveness than ask permission.
正是
Exactly.
那他的下一步行动会是啥
So what's his next step?
他得离开洛杉矶
He's got to get out of Los Angeles,
这意味着他需要有一本新护照
which means he needs a new passport,
他需要一个新的身份 而且根据目前他被通缉的情况
he needs a new identity and, given the heat that's on him,
他的新身份必须完美无瑕
it's got to be perfect.
这任务可不简单啊 Deeks先生
That's a large task, Mr. Deeks.
Thapa对这城市里很陌生
Thapa's a stranger in this city.
他怎么知道该去哪
How would he know where to go?
我告诉他了
Because I told him.
我 呃
I, um...
提到了Glandale里 一处亚美尼亚犯罪集团办假证的地方
mentioned the Armenian Mob franchise in Glendale.
那里由一个叫Talita Pambakian的女人运作
It's run by a woman named Talita Pambakian.
- 你知道她的住址  - 我花了两个星期
- You know her location?  - I spent two weeks
为洛杉矶警方做卧底 渗透进他她的组织
infiltrating her group, working undercover for LAPD.
我们建立了联系 她以为我是个律师
We established contact. She thinks I'm a lawyer.
然后发生什么了
And what happened?
她察觉了他身边的另一个卧底
She found out there was another cop working undercover
并且将他射杀了
and she shot him in the head.
显然 洛杉矶警方中止了行动 把我拉了出来
Obviously, LAPD shut it down and then they pulled me out.
你现在想重新建立联系
And you want to reestablish contact.
Thapa正在去见她的路上
Thapa's on his way to see her right now.
我只需要在那里制服他就行了
All I got to do is beat him there.
你需要一套西装
You need a suit.
Hetty向你做简报了吗
Hetty brief you?
嗯
Yeah.
我们评估了行动地点
We assessed the location in Ops
说实话 我不喜欢
and, honestly, I don't like it.
如果有什么意外 我们很难赶来
Makes it impossible for us to reach you if something goes wrong.
没得选 这是唯一的办法
Not much of a choice. It's the only way.
或者你其实觉得这是唯一能挽回
Or you mean the only way to redeem yourself
关于旅店及Thapa这些事的方法
for the hotel and Thapa?
你能帮我个忙吗
Can you do something for me?
啥
What?
就现在 你能不能假装我不是Deeks
Can you, for a second, just pretend that I'm not Deeks
而你也不是Kensi
and, for a second, pretend that you're not Kensi
我们不是搭档
and that we're not partners
我们也没有天天去拯救世界什么的
and no one's trying to save the planet?
能不能假装我们只是
Can we pretend for a second that we're just a boy and a girl
一起厮混的男女
who are hanging out?
我们能
We can...
开着我的皮卡 去买冰淇淋
drive around in my pickup truck, go get ice cream,
打保龄球
go bowling.
我们有无限多的可能
But that's the thing because the possibilities are endless.
我们很年轻
We're young.
我们有大把的时间
We have all the time in the world.
我是Fern 嗨
My name is Fern. Hi.
你是Fern
You're Fern.
呃 见到你 很高兴 Fern 我是Max
Well, so nice to... so nice to meet you, Fern. I'm Max.
幸会幸会
Nice to meet you.
今晚有空吗
You have any plans for tonight?
不知道 这很复杂
I don't know. It's complicated.
呃 在我看来没啥复杂的嘛
Well, not from where I'm standing, it's not.
我有男朋友了
I have a boyfriend.
我也有女朋友了
So is my girlfriend.
西装很漂亮 是啊
That's a nice suit. Yeah.
问题是
The problem with it is
这衣服太紧了
that's it's too-too tight.
很难藏起武器
It's gonna be hard to conceal a weapon.
Talita对我做的第一件事就会是搜身
The first thing Talita's guys are gonna do are pat me down.
他们总要发现的
They're gonna find it anyway.
给你
Here.
不 我 我不能拿这个
No, I-I can't take that.
我的搭档不能毫无防范地去执行任务
My partner doesn't go unarmed.
拿着它
Take it.
我还从没遇到一个女人给我 呃 她的刀
I've never had a girl give me her, uh... knife before.
这是不是意味着我们正式确定了关系
Does that mean that we are... official?
呃 有时候这仅仅是把刀而已
Eh, sometimes a knife is just a knife.
来吧 Eric 给我们报告
All right, take us through it, Eric.
那些墙很结实 厚而且结实
Those walls are concrete. Thick concrete.
结构也很完整 唯一的入口
The structural integrity's sound, the only way in
是通过前门 外面有两个守卫
is through the front door. There are the two guards
可能在墙后还有更多人
out front and probably more inside that we can't see.
Talita在哪
Where's Talita located?
结构图表明
Uh, schematics show
建筑的后方有一间办公室
an office in the back of the building,
但是 要去那里的话
but you'll have to make it through
你必须穿过那条狭窄的走廊
a narrow hallway to get there.
致命的危险区
Fatal funnel.
- 战略上的噩梦  - 的确是
- Strategic nightmare. - Yeah.
信号良好吗
Comm's good?
很清楚
Loud and clear.
我是来见Talita的
Here to see Talita.
你有预约吗
- You got an appointment?
告诉她Marty Finch来见她了
Tell her Marty Finch is here to see her.
你或许是个警察呢 Marty Finch
Maybe you're a cop, Marty Finch.
打电话给她的律师
Call her lawyer.
真巧 因为我就是她的律师
Well, that's perfect timing 'cause I am her lawyer.
有个叫Marty Finch的人在这儿
Guy named Marty Finch is here.
把他带到后面来
Send him back.
好的
Yeah.
他可以进去
He's good.
我们走
Let's go.
右手边第一道门
First door on the right.
你是那位在09年解决了
You're the guy who made those narco charges go away
那些关于毒品指控的人吗
back in '09?
现在交出你身上的武器
Hand over any weapons now.
我没带武器
I'm not carrying.
在找线路
Look for a wire, too...
那个区域是建筑里的
Comms deadzone in that sector
通信盲区 我无能为力了
of the building, guys. My hands are tied.
那我们等
Then we wait.
你没问题吧
You good?
我很好
I'm good.
你很享受嘛
You enjoying yourself?
他没带武器
He's clean.
从坟墓里爬出来了 律师
Back from the dead, counselor?
Talita 我没死 只是非常忙
Not dead, Talita, just incredibly busy.
如果你不为我工作
If you're not working for me,
那都一样
it's all the same.
来听听你的说辞吧
Let's hear your pitch.
你是来推销业务 是吧
You've come to peddle your wares, right?
说到这儿 我是不是该说你依然漂亮
Is this the part where I tell you you still look good
还有 你的生意越来越旺了
and your business is thriving?
问题是我从不对顾客说谎
Only problem is I don't lie to clients.
你死定了 Talita
You're screwed, Talita.
洛杉矶警方会来找你麻烦
LAPD's coming for you.
他们知道当卧底出现在我家门口时 会发生什么
They knowwhat happens when undercovers show up at my door.
对你来说很不幸 他们惦记着你
And, unfortunately for you, they don't forget.
我线人说你现在还有个人在找你麻烦
My source says you have another one coming your way right now.
小个子 有一米六七 深色皮肤 还带着一套卧底说辞
Small guy, maybe five-five, dark skin with an undercover
需要返回印度的伪造文件
story about needing forged papers to get back to India.
我听着呢 Finch
I'm waiting, Finch.
你说啥呢 等啥
What are you talking about? Waiting for what?
那家伙可是个专业人士
That was pro bono.
我还漂亮吗
Do I still look good or not?
我之前说谎了
I lied before.
你看起来还是很漂亮
You still look good.
你想要啥
What do you want?
你有一群笨蛋带着枪
You got a lot of meatheads carrying guns,
但没人能帮你重建你整个组织
but you don't have anybody that can restructure
让它合法 那 Talita
your entire organization and make it legit. That, Talita,
就是我想要的
is what I want.
还是以前的价格吗
Still billing the same rate?
不 不 现在是大人物规则了
No, no. Big boy rules now.
不再收律师费了 我要抽成
No more retainers. I need a percentage.
大人物规则
"Big boy rules"?
是
Yeah.
我喜欢
I like that.
- 小心我的西装  - 起来
- Easy on the suit.  - Get up.
你知道 我不喜欢你09年时不守诺言
You see, I don't like the one-and-done thing
打一枪就跑
that you pulled back in '09.
把事情搞定
Make things right.
跟我表表衷心
Show me you're loyal.
你指的是啥
What are you talking about?
在大人物的桌旁有你的位置
There's a seat for you at my big boy table.
但你得去争取
But you got to take it.
带他去
Show him.
你线人说得对
Your source was right.
这家伙一出现
This guy showed up,
说他急需一个身份证
said he needed clean I.D. Fast.
但是如果他是个警察
But if he's a cop,
为什么 当我们搜遍了他全身
how come, when we shook him down,
只发现一个U盘
all we found was a thumb drive?
我不知道什么U盘
I don't know anything about a thumb drive.
现在我拥有U盘了
Now that I have it,
我不需要他了 是吧
I don't need him, do I?
证明你的忠诚
Prove your loyalty.
拿着
Take it.
小个子忘记了
Little man here forgot
在小偷之间是没有荣誉可言的
there's no honor among thieves.
他有段时间没消息了
He's been dark for a while.
我们知道里面有问题
We knew this building had problems.
- 听着 Talita 我不杀人的  - 也许不是为了生存
- Listen, Talita, I don't shoot people. Maybe not for a living,
不过任何人都可以在一个受了伤的人面前开枪的
but anyone can stand before a beaten man and pull a trigger.
我只放了一个子弹在那枪里
I only put one bullet in that gun.
别打歪了
Don't miss.
要么现在 Finch
Now, Finch,
要么我们就会有两具尸体挂在这些吊钩上了
or we're going to have two bodies hanging from hooks.
Eric
Eric?
信号已经是最大限度增幅了
The signal's on full boost.
我们啥都不能做
There's nothing we can do.
在那地方
Lots of guns
有好多枪
inside that place.
我们进去
We go in,
我们就会遭遇强火力
we're going in big.
我们再等一分钟
Let's let it play out for another 60 seconds,
然后我们攻入
then we breach.
明白
We clear?
Kensi
Kensi?
Kensi...!
妹的 Eric 告诉洛杉矶警方我们要行动了
Damn it. Eric, tell LAPD we're going in hot.
收到
Copy that.
Kensi
Kensi!
放下枪 联邦探员
Drop it! Federal agent!
Deeks
Deeks!
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你差点打爆我的头
You almost took my head off.
谁开的那枪
Who takes that shot?
你怎么现在才来
Took you long enough.
Thapa 跟我走
Stay with me, Thapa.
我向你们道歉
I owe you guys an apology.
对不起
I'm sorry.
告诉我你拿到了那个U盘
Tell me you secured the thumb drive,
我们会忘了这事儿
we're going to forget about it.
我没拿
I don't have it.
谁拿了 Deeks
Well, who has it-- Deeks?
呃 没有
Um, no.
我的意思是 他要是拿了他就会说了 是吧
I mean, he would have said if he had it, right?
但我
But I...
好吧 肯定不可能是廓尔喀人拿着U盘
Okay, there's no way the Gurkha held onto it,
所以是在这儿的某个地方 我 我会找到的
so it's got to be here somewhere. I-I will find it.
我猜是在夹克的衣袋里
I'm thinking inside jacket pocket,
左边
left side.
我猜是右边
I'll go right.
找到了
Bingo.
猜得好
Nice call.
Kensi 道歉接受了
Kensi... apology accepted.
去和你搭档汇合吧
Go be with your partner.
谢谢
Thanks.
这件事带来了一大堆麻烦
Lot of trouble over this thing.
你对了
That's right,
所以我们得把它放在安全的地方
so let's put it somewhere safe.
你知道吗
You know what?
这主意太好了
That's a good idea.
安全为上 G
Watch my back, G.
预备 抬
Here we go.
他流了不少血 但是会活下来的
He lost a lot of blood but he'll live.
廓尔喀人的流言 绝不夸张
Gurkhas, believe the hype.
Deeks
Deeks...
我准备跟他去医院
I'm gonna go with him to the hospital.
不 嘿 哇 拜托 先等我
No, hey, whoa, please, let me just...
我只是想跟你说点事
I just want to say something.
嗯
Yeah.
我们要搞清楚
We're gonna figure this out.
我们只是谈论它
All we got to do is talk about it.
但是你不 你不真的想
Okay, but you don't, you don't really like
谈这个吧
the talking about it.
是 但是我还是说出来比较好
Yeah, but I promise I'll be better at talking about this.
什么意思 你的"这个"指什么
What do you, what do you mean by "This"?
这个 你懂的
This... you know.
这个事吗
This thing?
是 我们的 事
Yes, our... thing.
我很抱歉 只是 我没 我没听见
I'm sorry, just... I didn't, I didn't hear you
因为很多人在旁走过
'cause there were so many people walking by.
你大一点声说 哪怕只为我说一次
If you could just maybe say it louder just for me.
就一次 说出来
Just once, just say it.
我恨你
I hate you.
不可能 不能 你不恨我
You don't, you don't, you don't hate me.
- 我们的事  - 哇
- Our thing. - Wow.
你也必须向我保证一些事
You have to promise me something, too, though.
任何事都可以
Anything.
你要对我有耐心 可以吗
Promise you'll be patient with me?
呦 该走了
Yo, got to roll.
今晚见吗
See you tonight?
没问题
Yeah.
帮我个忙 Fern
You do me a favor, Fern?
任何事
Anything.
把那衬衫烧了吧
Can you burn that shirt for me?
在我还没察觉到自己人性向上的一面时 你却发现了它
You saw good in me when I could not even see it in myself.
我永远不会忘的 先生
I will never forget that, sahib.
呃 你在机场的时候是不是准备
You know, you actually started to tell me something
告诉我一些事
back at the airstrip.
你想告诉我渡过冰湖的唯一方法
You started to tell me the only way to cross a frozen lake.
别急
Do not run.
稳步向前
Walk slowly.
心无旁鹜
Stop to look at everything.
保持从容不迫
Take your time.
她会等着你的
She will wait for you.
好吧
Okay.
你在等Deeks吗
You waiting for Deeks?
是的
Yeah.
打包你的东西 Blye探员
Pack your things, Agent Blye.
什么
Excuse me?
一架C-130在等你
There's a C-130 waiting for you.
你被借调了
You've been reassigned.
借调
Reassigned?
额 Hetty 副主任Granger说
Uh, Hetty, Assistant Director Granger says
我被借调了
I've been reassigned.
没错
That's correct.
你需要一件干净的衬衫
You'll be needing a clean shirt,
Blye小姐
Miss Blye.
为什么他这么做
Why is he doing that?
他没有 是我
He's not. I am.
我什么时候能回来
When will I be back?
等任务结束
When the job's done.
动身吧 Blye探员
Let's move, Agent Blye.
这是什么情况 Hetty
What's this about, Hetty?
按需知密 先生们
"Need to know," Gentlemen.
你能不把我们当棋子般动吗
You ever gonna stop moving us around like pieces in a chess game?
我不动棋子 Callen先生
I don't move pieces, Mr. Callen.
我动棋盘
I move the board.
晚安
Good night.
拜托 我犯了所有交通条例回来
Oh, come on, I break every traffic law on the planet
而她已经离开了吗
to get here and she already left?
你的搭档被调离了 Deeks先生
Your partner's been reassigned, Mr. Deeks.
你什么意思 什么意思 被借调
What do you mean? What do you mean, reassigned?
一个机密任务
A classified mission.
执行时间多长的机密任务
A c-classified mission for how long?
看情况
Indefinitely.
看起来很眼熟啊
That looks familiar.
这是她父亲的
It was her dad's.
这算一份重礼了
Well... that is quite a gift.
有时候 这仅仅是把刀而已
Well, sometimes a knife is just a knife.
现在她把这个托付给你
And now she's entrusted it to you.
我还应该知道什么吗 Hetty
Anything else I should know, Hetty?
扣好纽扣 Deeks先生
Button up, Mr. Deeks.
外面好冷
It's cold out there.
== 开头G神吐糟 ==
== Callen跑步追不上大黑了！！加强运动啊 ==
== 毛茸茸左手开枪帅爆了！！！ ==
== 话唠的解药难道是K姐吗？！ ==
== 廓尔喀大兵一下子就看出毛茸茸在想啥了 ==
== 楼上的没错↑↑↑Deeks你果然瞒不住啊 ==
== 我DK党就这么被拆了吗 ==
== K姐快回来啊 Hetty好狠啊 ==
== Deeks最近吃药吃多了 话真少 ==
== 果然Deeks话少了 都被大黑吐槽了 ==
== Deeks你敢换个袜子吗 太难看了 ==
== K姐表白是傲娇了吗 ==
== 最后一个人好可怜啊 ==
== 导演你要不要这么狠 又拆散毛茸茸和K姐 ==
== 【H-SGDK】字幕组欢迎各位加入
有意者请加QQ群109164858，注明 字幕组+申请职位即可 ==
== 海军罪案调查处:洛杉矶 第五季 第10集【H-SGDK】字幕组倾情奉献 ==
前一句是俚语 不过直译会成"给你一分钱 告诉我你想什么事情"
廓尔喀刀闻名 尼泊尔的国刀 较重的刀刃能造成很深的伤口 甚至能切断肌肉与骨头
近期最出名的是生化危机3里 女主角的形象
考据狂表示较精准为1.62米……
简称ISI 巴基斯坦情报部门
Kali 印度教女神 中文译为时母 雪山神女的化身之一
因1971年印巴战争时的表现 在1973年获得印度陆军元帅军衔
西孟加拉邦 位于印度东部
Quick Reaction Force
海关不允许他出境
在教父 第二部中 有Mike杀死自己的哥哥Fredo的情节
警犬在欧美被称为K-9 英语canine的同音异义语词
I've been there, I've done that, I got the T-shirt.
俚语 意指完成一切
Fatal funnel 属于必经之地 敌人枪口势必瞄准之处
C-130 中型战术运输机